<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shit Brett Thinks</title>
    <description>Stuff I feel is worth writing, whether for the benefit of others, or my future self.
</description>
    <link>http://brett.geek.nz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://brett.geek.nz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 18:34:29 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 18:34:29 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Practices Influence Community</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hello, I'm Brett; Software Developer by day, Dancer by night.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started off presentations with lines like this more times that I care to admit. Talking at conferences, there’s
almost always an obligatory “Who am I”/”Why am I qualified to talk about this” slide/section. This topic, on culture,
community, practices and how they all interact is something that I’ve been thinking about for a while. I don’t have a
degree in psychology or social sciences, I haven’t run any tests, and I’ve got a relatively low sample size. I don’t
even have well-quantified, numerical data. I’ve spent 5-6 years in various dancing circles/communities (using this last
word loosely in some cases), and probably about twice as long in various businesses related to software development. I
have absorbed a large history of experience with &lt;em&gt;living&lt;/em&gt; in different cultures/communities, applying practices (or
not), and observing affects of practices on culture/communities in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software development, especially in environments that practice tenets of “Agile” or “Extreme Programming”, we have a
particular practice called “pairing”. When pairing, you work with another person - often another developer - and work on
a piece of work together, ideally using the same keyboard/mouse/screen. Pairing enables a kind of instantaneous peer
review, ensures that if one person doesn’t catch an error then the other one should. It’s also great for sharing
knowledge, aides problem solving, and generally improves relationships between two people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In partner dance, we have the same concept, except it’s just assumed - it’s a partner dance, so you must be dancing with
a partner, right? It’s just called dancing. It shares much in common with the software development practice; You’re
working (though dancing seldom feels like work) with someone, and instead of a keyboard, mouse and screen, you’re
interfacing directly with the other person, typically with some kind of hand/limb-based contact. If you’ve never danced
with your partner before, you can quickly assess the compatibility of their dancing to yours (not be confused with
“level” of dancing), and knowledge sharing, problem solving and relationship building all come from occupying the same
space and communicating (through voice, dance or facial expressions) at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all sounds good. In fact, this all sounds… normal. Expected, in fact?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another practice in software development is “pair rotation” - quite simply, frequently changing who you are pairing
with. In dancing, this is similar to finding a new dance partner on the social dance floor at the start of the next song
OR - in some software development environments/dance formats - partway during a song. In dance communities for
“social-first” dance styles, this is super common. We rotate partners frequently during classes, workshops, and many
people challenge themselves to getting a dance with as many people they can during social time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also, generally speaking, good. You knowledge share, problem solve, and build relationships (or at least a
rapport) with many developers/dancers, and this is effectively like a kind of social lubrication; communication builds
community; they share half a word, after all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where we start to get into murky waters is when competition becomes involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some styles of partner dance, in competition, uphold the ability to dance well with many different people as being,
shall we say, “the most important”. They do this my only measuring progress on this alone; sure, you receive accolades
and prizes for dancing well with just one person (against other strong partnerships), but you will only gain rank 
(usually received as points) by being in the top X many people to be really good at dancing with many other dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, other styles of partner dance won’t hold this position at all; You can gain rank for dancing well with just
one person, as well as gaining rank for dancing well with many. And why not? This ability to dance well with one
specific other person is venerable in it’s own right; you can receive prizes, why not have this ability reflected by
change rank as well? As a matter of course, it’s much easier to train with just one person, and as a partnership you can
theoretically reach higher heights by knowing each others intricacies, building new movements, combos, and a new dance
language between each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But alas, there is a dark-side when this single-partner focus becomes the emphasis of the dance competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For software development, there isn’t really “competition” in the sense of direct, head-to-head, who-is-better-than-whom
 competing, either between individuals or pairs. Obviously there can be competition at the business level, aiming to get
 a product out to market before a competitor does, and this is when these values are tested. Does a software development
 team, under extra pressure to get a product out to market, stick to the virtues of pair rotation, and even pairing, or
 does it let those practices fall apart, banking on the work of highly-compatible, high-output pairs (or even
 individuals) to get “over the line”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dance communities are quite often open, welcoming groups. Of course, individuals can make or break the experience for
others, but more generally, social dancing communities want more people to dance with, or for more people to experience
the wonderful world of dancing. This is especially true of communities that favour the ability to dance with many people
over the ability of an individual to dance with one specific person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social dance communities that favour and reward partnerships, I have observed, can tend towards being more insular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take a reductive view; why would a dance partnership hone their ability to dance with a plethora of people, when they
could instead hone their ability to dance well together, and potentially progress faster as a pair? They train together,
they build their repertoire together. It benefits them less to attend a class and learn techniques in a group, when they
could work together and learn techniques at a faster pace, because they’re on the same level and are speaking the same
dance-language dialect as one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your partnership dancing is rewarded and you gain rank together, this is a no-brainer. A partnership could go
unseen by others for months, even their local studio/company, and show up at competition and wow everyone, including the
locals, their “peers”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 15:16:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2019/05/08/how-practices-influence-community.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2019/05/08/how-practices-influence-community.html</guid>
        
        <category>dancing</category>
        
        <category>software-development</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>community</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Far Can This Go?</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;actually-pretty-far&quot;&gt;actually, pretty far.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is part 3 in a series of posts about a little electronics project I started at work. &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/07/11/i-couldnt-do-that-could-i.html&quot;&gt;You can find the first post here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some time has passed between the writing of the last post and this one. I will endeavour to keep things in an approximately correct chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the last post, I had a project that had legs, but how far can it go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure when I got the idea, or what I had originally thought of, but I knew I wanted an installation that would be relatively permanent. The previous electronics project I’d worked on (&lt;a href=&quot;http://hooroo.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/arduino-build-light/&quot;&gt;the build light&lt;/a&gt;) was pretty sketchy, pretty much just a small Arduino-compatible, a NeoPixel ring and a proto-board. And to be fair, that was holding up pretty well, in it’s little plastic box on the wall. But this new project was going to something else. I was going to have to step up my game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rough_measurements.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rough Measurements&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I downloaded EAGLE, a free-to-use, but otherwise proprietary CAD tool for designing Printed Circuit Boards. (This kind of tool might also be called an “EDA”, for “Electronic Design Automation”). I decided I would design a board to house one of the 7-segment displays, the decoder and other supporting circuitry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how was I going to get the data out to multiple displays? Directly driving all those decoder inputs, while being fewer than the segments themselves, was going to get very unwieldly, very quickly. I’d already had this idea in my head that I wanted to be able to chain these things on to each other, and there existed just the thing to do that - the humble Shift Register.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily I had a shift register lying around from an Arduino Getting Started kit from Sparkfun, so I took advantage of using that to test that this would work… and of course, it did! So now I had these decoders that took 4 bits of data each, and shift registers that could handle 8 bits… What else could I do? Given a 5V signal source, which the shift register effectively was, I could directly drive the decimal point on the individual displays… I could even drive the individual Output Enable pins on the decoders themselves, wouldn’t that be great?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I got stuck on something - the dimensions of the individual display units themselves were pushing the design size out past the lowest price point available from the company I had chosen for printing the boards - and I’d chosen them because they were both affordable and reliable. I’d had suggestions from a friend to build the circuit on a smaller board and connect to the end of the display with a wire harness, but I decided that it would be better to ensure that the displays had the support of a rigid board from end to end. In for a penny in for a pound, why not put two displays on one board? It wasn’t going to change the cost after this latest decision, and so it was!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was now going with two displays, I threw out the ideas around driving the decimal points at all, and also individually controlling the Output Enable pins. Two sets of four binary-coded-decimal bits fit perfectly into the  eight bits of a single shift register, so that was just going to have to do. After iterating on the design for a while, I sent the board off for printing (exciting!) and a few weeks later, having selected the cheap option to shipping, I received my first ever Printed Circuit Boards that I had designed myself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/many_like_them_but_these_are_mine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My First PCBs!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a certain feeling having something like these in front of you for the first time. I remember a giddy feeling, being almost unable to wait to get home and add the components to the board! That time was going to have to wait, because the boards beat the parts to delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/the_parts_arrived.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The parts have arrived&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about a week, the parts arrived from element14 and I was able to get going! I was so excited to finally have everything, I had to build one! Finally, around midnight, I had my first display board completely built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/display_board_back.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Display board Back&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/display_board_front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Display board Front&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That wasn’t the end of it, though. For some reason, a couple of elements weren’t behaving as expected. It turned out that two elements were switched - lighting up when the other should have been - and I couldn’t just change it in code because I had a hardware decoder sitting in there decoding my (correct!) decimal values. Sadly, I’d gotten something wrong in the schematic diagram - actually, I’d like to blame whoever designed the schematic part in Eagle for the BCD decoder, witness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fault_of_the_other.png&quot; alt=&quot;Confusing Eagle part&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the F and G pins on U2/CD4511BE (the BCD decoder) are flipped! I wasn’t about to go and get this reprinted - thankfully the fix for this was pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/easy_fix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crossed Resistors&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I set out to complete the rest of the boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/building_the_rest.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; alt=&quot;Building the remaining boards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/all_displays_finished.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; alt=&quot;The finished displays&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to mention another problem I had to overcome - I wasn’t going to be able to just throw 9V at whatever logic was powering this thing and expect it to come out the other end unscathed. Previously I had been using an Arduino, sending 5V signals to the BCD decoders. In order to get anything to display I had to power the decoders separately with 9V batteries, but doesn’t that sound a bit dangerous for the Arduino, or whatever else might take it’s place in the future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the signals on this board only travel in one direction, I was pretty comfortable with the idea of using plain ol’ transistors as level shifters. From studying how transistors work, I prototyped on a breadboard and assured myself that this would work. Effectively, transistors can be used to take a low voltage input and produce a higher-voltage output. The only problem is that the transistor inverts the signal being input - so a LOW input signal will come out as HIGH, and vice versa. Luckily, this is easily fixed in the Arduino code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for my next update, where I talk about maybe controlling this chain of displays with something other than an Arduino!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 20:54:54 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2016/12/13/how-far-can-this-go.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2016/12/13/how-far-can-this-go.html</guid>
        
        <category>electronics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wouldn't It Be Awesome If...</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;aka-research-development-and-scope-creep&quot;&gt;a.k.a Research, Development and Scope-Creep&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is part 2 in a series of posts about a little electronics project I started at work. &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/07/11/i-couldnt-do-that-could-i.html&quot;&gt;You can find the first post here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As said in my previous post, I wanted to build a device to show financial goals or the company’s financial milestones. I wanted this to be visible from across the room, so it had to be big… what could I use that would fit the bill?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/split_flap_display.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Split Flap Display&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever seen those large old boards at some airports or other travel ports that make a whole lot of clacking noise? You know, the ones that physically turn over a set of cards until it gets to the right number? They’re called Split Flaps, and are (quite obviously) a mechanical device that can be electrically driven/controlled. Each character you want to display is split in half across two flaps, and a ring of flaps is flipped around until the desired character is displaying at the front. This can be driven by a stepper motor. Those would be sweet as to get running and have some numbers displayed on… If only they weren’t about $100 apiece for a single module! There are some resources online about how to build them, but I’m not about to endeavour on a journey to learn the intricacies and mechanics of a split-flap display when mechanics is probably my weakest area of expertise. Also, thinking about it now, that noise would have been SOOO obnoxious. Split-Flaps: Scratched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/alarm_clock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Digital Alarm Clock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my mind went to alarm clocks - digital alarm clocks specifically. I personally think that the seven-segment displays on alarm clocks give numbers much more tactility than just being put up on a monitor, and they’re relatively easy to find, so let’s follow this path some more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jaycar, a massive hobbyist/electronics chain here in Australia and NZ, stocks these displays in a few different sizes. I wanted this display to be seen from across the office, so naturally this meant big - how big can you get? Having a nosey around the Melbourne CBD Jaycar store, I grabbed a couple of 2.3” large displays, and a couple of driver ICs for them, all for the purposes of testing and determining if they were going to be the right tool for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent almost a full day trying to figure out the pin-out of the displays I bought! It didn’t help that I was trying to use a 5V source, and after a bit of… “study” (RTFM/RTF Datasheet) I discovered that each of the main elements had 4 LEDs in series to light it up. In a bit of a hail-mary effort to try and get this thing to light up I pulled out a 9V battery and started feeding that in and once I found ground, hey presto, it works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/it_works.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;It's working!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, each of the main elements (segments) of the display used 4 LEDs in series (2 for the decimal point). Each of these LEDs was contributing a 1.8V voltage drop, summing up in series to 7.2V, which explains the failure of the 5V source to light anything up! During this period of discovery I think I also burnt out the dot on one of the displays, but that’s ok, it was all in the name of research!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to mention at this point that the “driver” IC is actually what’s called a “BCD decoder,” or “Binary-Coded Decimal decoder.” It takes 4 inputs A, B, C and D, each coresponding to the numbers 1, 2, 4 and 8. With any combination of these numbers you can make any decimal number, which the decoder decodes and sends out through it’s 7 outputs, each corresponding to a segment on the seven-segment display. Some BCD decoders have slightly different input schemes, such as A=1, B=2, C=2 and D=4, which prevents you from giving it input that it can’t display. The decoders I have just blank out the display when the number if is given doesn’t fit within the range of 0-9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea seemed to have some legs, so I thought I’d move ahead with this and see how it plays out. I ignored all the problems that were surfacing in my head, such as power consumption, how I’d power it, how I’d control it, etc. Those were problems for another day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 12:34:20 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2016/07/16/wouldnt-it-be-awesome-if.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2016/07/16/wouldnt-it-be-awesome-if.html</guid>
        
        <category>electronics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Couldn't Do That! ...Could I?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It all started with a meeting about our goals in the office, and how our performance for the year was to be measured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a Software Developer on the delivery team at Hooroo, aka Qantas Hotels and Jetstar Hotels. While being a seperate company, we utilise the HR of Jetstar, and thus have some of their overhead in the company, which includes these KPIs and other stuff that generally nobody likes, but everybody lives with. If there’s a story there, it’s for another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, in my particular team at Hooroo we were having this meeting about how the specific technical KPIs applied to us. We have some about Technical Competency, Continuous Improvement and so on, but we also have this strange one, “Engaging with Financial Goals”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does it mean to engage with financial goals? I don’t know either! So I thought I’d start with just getting something financially related displaying… somewhere, y’know, visible. Somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about some people, but if I don’t see something in a non-intrusive way every day, I find it hard to interact with, or remember to look for it. Emails, for instance, can be quite intrusive, if not just noisy. We totally get the relevant financial figures coming into our email inboxes on a day to day basis - along with lots of other things. Noise, alert fatigue, whatever - this has all been filtered out of my inbox so I can see what I think is really important, which are usually one-off, non-repeating comms with other humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a couple of monitors up on the walls, showing a couple of different sets of information - we’ve got the status of our application builds, the total number of visitors currently on our main website, and a map display of where high-value bookings have been made. &lt;a href=&quot;http://hooroo.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/arduino-build-light/&quot;&gt;We’ve also got what we call a “Build Light”&lt;/a&gt;, which is an aggregate view of the status of all of our builds. I had something to do with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally though, I think the monitors are boring, perhaps a little too easy to get information up on. Build Lights, on the other hand, that’s pretty cool! How can I apply the build-light hardware foo to showing financial goals? Wouldn’t it be awesome to build a low-tech, multi-digit display to show our financial goals or current performance on? Perhaps using something like the kind of digits you used to see on your alarm clock, back when it was still a box that sat on your bedside table, before it was your phone…? But I couldn’t do that… Could I?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 22:37:23 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2016/07/11/i-couldnt-do-that-could-i.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2016/07/11/i-couldnt-do-that-could-i.html</guid>
        
        <category>electronics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cambodia Trip - Day 1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get dressed, pack the last few items and out the door. Ready to go by… 6:15?! I wouldn’t say that we were ready to go, we had enjoyed Vietnam so much, but we were packed, on our feet, and standing outside the hotel we’d rather recently checked out of. The restaurant wasn’t even open by this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a drastic change to the flow of events so far, started the day by loading our heavy luggage onto cyclos, then proceeded to walk a few blocks. We walked to a local park area, where we passed people playing games, dancing, crimping… Anything for a bit of exercise. It was here that we identified our bags once again, had them tagged, then boarded a public bus - the Mekong Express.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our new tour guide, Sum (pronounced with the vowel sound of oomph or umph) said there was method to this 6:15am madness. Along the way to Phnom Penh we needed to cross the Mekong Delta, and the only way to do this currently was by ferry. In his experience, the ferry always seems to get stuck partway, probably due to the busyness of the area. He didn’t want for us to be roasting in the afternoon heat while we waited to get back to land. But more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was two hours before we reached the country border. During this time we filled out forms and were treated to a variety of western and Cambodian pop music. Thankfully we were given a small packed breakfast from the hotel, and received a small snack on the bus, so we weren’t starving the whole way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The border was very busy. If you think emigration/immigration at the airport sucks, you probably don’t want to go through a land crossing. The bus company made the process a bit easier, taking all the passports from the bus occupants to the counter at once, so we just had to wait until our names were called. We had gotten of the bus and entered a building to do this crossing. Once through, however, we were only half done. What we’d just been through was exiting Vietnam. We were now on international soil, and had yet to enter Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those with Cambodian visas, the next part was relatively straightforward. We all got back into the bus and drove over to the Cambodian border entry building. Those with visas could go straight through to the immigration desks and get their entry stamps. For those of us without our visas, we had given our passports back to the assistant from the bus, who went to a small building outside where the visas could be bought from. Our Vietnamese visas, which we sent our passports away for before our trip, cost about $95 (AUD) each. Comparatively, Cambodian visas at the border cost $25 (USD) each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just about everything in Cambodia is compared with Vietnam, in my head. The roads (and traffic) are no exception. Roads in Cambodia… Have been found wanting. They are not as wide, occasionally they are just dirt, and with more cars and less motorbikes, there’s generally just less room. The countryside, however, is still beautiful. Since it’s tropical, you’ll find more “New Zealand green” than “Australian green”, much the same as Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were still about 5 hours away from Phnom Penh, and it took about 1 or 2 hours to get to the aforementioned ferry. Luckily, we only had about ten minutes stand still, and soon we were back on land. But not before seeing the sheer number of people heading in the other direction, many in motorbikes, and all unbelievably packed into the ferry going the other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About five minutes later we’d stopped again, this time to have lunch. We’d stopped outside a small collection of food stalls, all under one roof. You would be mistaken to think it was just one big cafe. Spoilt for choice, I went for rice noodles with chicken curry. For $2. I also discovered the flexibility of currency here - I actually paid one US dollar and 20,000 Vietnamese dong. Over the moon at the price, I was just as happy with the flavours - Cambodia uses a lot more spice (note: not necessarily spicy) and the flavour palette just woke up my tongue. In Vietnam, at lot of food was oily and less strong in flavour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phnom Penh is a strange mixture of old and new. Many of the buildings are rather squat, with a few skyscrapers dotted around. We dropped our bags off at the hotel and went for a short tuktuk tour around the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We visited the hill and the statue of the woman the city was named after, though we didn’t go inside the temple on the hill. I was getting rather hungry by this time.  We went onwards, catching the tuktuks to the next destination, a famed roundabout. In the middle of this roundabout was a tower, erected after the reigning king of the time drove the French out of the country. Nearby was a statue of the king, facing east in the traditional Buddhist fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking along the river we soon reached our destination for dinner, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yourphnompenh.com/river-crown/&quot;&gt;River Crown Restaurant&lt;/a&gt;. The menu was mostly western, which was disappointing. But it was happy hour, so I ordered a pint and a pizza. Besides, Phnom Penh was apparently not the place to get good Cambodian food made properly. Still, I probably didn’t need the whole pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long day, there was no bandying about considering going to the hotel bar. Straight to bed, and an early night for Brett.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/12/cambodia-trip-day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/12/cambodia-trip-day-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vietnam Trip - Day 15</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-15&quot;&gt;Day 15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was another early day, and after another breakfast we got into our bus and left the hotel for a day out on the Mekong Delta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we weren’t going to visit the floating villages/markets, but it was still a good experience nonetheless. We were going to visit a couple of islands before heading over to tour the Ben Tre province. On one island we learned how coconuts are harvested and all different parts are used. Most prominent was the manufacturing of coconut candy, while there were also carvings,  and some coconut husks were used for burning to cook the coconut candy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While on this island I also got to have my first experience holding a snake. This one was rather large but wasn’t poisonous, instead it was a constrictor. I didn’t get any of my own photos of this, but one of the others got one of me with the snake,  so hopefully later on after the trip I’ll be able to post proof!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another island we visited we got to visit was more for trying various tropical fruit. These were mostly your standard watermelon, pineapple and mango, we also had fresh jackfruit and a special red dragonfruit (normally, dragonfruit has white flesh). We were also treated to some traditional Vietnamese music and singing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we left for another, larger island in the Ben Tre province. We took small row boats up a small river,  surrounded by water coconuts and other flora. After about  15 minutes we disembarked, and it was time for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch was a five course meal, starting with fried fish in fresh spring rolls, moving through steamed prawns, pork pancakes and some deliciously seasoned chicken. As per usual, the final course was a fresh fruit dessert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had enough time before leaving for a bit of rest, and we were surround by hammocks. Some of us rested for a short while in the hammocks until it was time to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was to be my first tuktuk experience. These tuktuks had an open roof, so we got on the back and put helmets on. Occasionally,  we would duck to avoid low hanging branches. They took us for a tour through Ben Tre Province, ending at a harbour where our original boat was waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed back to the mainland, and loaded back into the bus. It was a couple of hours back to the city. Once we arrived, we had a couple of hours before our final group dinner. Some of the group were finishing their tour here in Ho Chi Minh City, but six of us were continuing on to Cambodia. Those continuing on from our group were myself and my two companions, and a family of three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for those of us continuing onwards,  we had a new group meeting to attend, where we met our new guide and the new group. There were none others going on the trip, all of whom had been together on another tour through Vietnam, though they had skipped Nha Trang and flown from Da Nang directly to Ho Chi Minh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only had a short amount of time left before it was time to go for our final dinner with our old group. Tonight we would in style. We went to the top floor of the Palace Saigon Hotel, to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g293925-d1770187-Reviews-Lemongrass-Ho_Chi_Minh_City.html&quot;&gt;Lemongrass Restaurant&lt;/a&gt;. Here we had our own private room, shelled out for overly expensive drinks, and rather tasty food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we celebrated our tour guide, who really made the trip special for us. John, the best talker of the group, gave a great speech, sprinkling some lighthearted flak throughout. Afterwards, one of the girls presented our guide with our tip that we’d organised for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We paid the bill and headed up to the rooftop, which had a stunning view of the burgeoning city, and we took pictures. Of each other and with our tour guide. We caught cabs back to the hotel, and went for one final drink at a nearby bar. We saw a lot of young men and women going upstairs, and reasoned that upstairs must be a karaoke or nightclub area. None of us went up to check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon we had finished our drinks, and it was time to say goodbye. We shook hands,  embraced and kissed this we wouldn’t see again, and said “See you in the morning to the others continuing on to Cambodia with us. Unfortunately we weren’t due much rest, as we had yet another early morning ahead…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/11/vietnam-trip-day-15.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/11/vietnam-trip-day-15.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vietnam Trip - Day 14</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-14&quot;&gt;Day 14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I not so much woke up, more opened my bleary eyes after a night of unrest. I’m not sure why this was the case, as I’d slept reasonably well in comparison in the last night train we’d been on. But alas, it was 4:30 in the morning, the train was showing down, and fairly soon it was time to wake up and smell the pungent aromas of Ho Chi Minh City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all piled into the bus without speed or enthusiasm. We reached our hotel and checked into day rooms,  and thankfully this one was a step up from the place we stayed in Nha Trang. We rotated through showering and getting freshened up (day rooms were always shared with others from the group), and soon enough  (or not), the restaurant was open for breakfast. Breakfast was okay, though I can’t say much can be appreciated when you’re tired. Well, coffee can be, and I downed about 4 of them before heading back downstairs to face the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we had the option of going to the Cu Chi Tunnels, where the Viet Cong held out against the Americans for a long time during the war. This was an interesting experience, not only because of what we saw and what they accomplished, but also the propagandist spin that we received. It also sound rather pro-Cong, which was quite opposed to the viewpoint of our guide from My Son, Mr Van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we got there, we stopped at a local house. Here we learned how to make rice paper, and even got to try doing it ourselves. This is not traditionally a man’s job, but I gave it a go anyway, and discovered I wasn’t too bad at it. At this house was also a garden and a pig farm. We got to feed the pigs, which were particularly large, and also got to see the piglets although they really didn’t liked to be picked up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found quite fascinating was learning how a pineapple grows. I’ve always had the mistaken impression that a pineapple just grows on a tree, whereas the reality is that the pineapple is the single flower of its own low-growing plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire area around the house, for miles around, was a rubber plantation. The plantation is wholly owned by the government, and any attempt to steal sap could get you shot. It is okay however to collect the seeds and plant your own rubber tree, and this house had a couple of their own trees, so we were able to see how rubber tree sap is collected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the tunnels, we got to see a lot of the kinds of traps that the Viet Cong used during the war, and also got to crawl through some section of tunnel as well. Some took one look at the tunnel entrance and Noped the hell out of there. I gave it a go, and opted to attempt the full 100 metres. I was at the back,  and I think that if I’d had somebody come up behind me I might have experienced some amount of claustrophobia. Thankfully I didn’t get to test this theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this traipse through the tunnels we were offered some tea and the cooked root of a plant called Cassava. You might better recognise this as tapioca, which is the name given to a particular form of extract from this plant. In Africa another name is given - Makihot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Went made our way back to the city, and met our guide at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g293925-d1122861-Reviews-Pho_2000-Ho_Chi_Minh_City.html&quot;&gt;Pho 2000&lt;/a&gt;, where we would follow in the steps of Bill Clinton and have a lunch of Pho. I don’t have much to compare this to, but I think the Pho was pretty good. Street lunch we went back to the hotel to collect the few people who didn’t come to the tunnels, and headed out for a city tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We visited the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g293925-d311103-Reviews-War_Remnants_Museum-Ho_Chi_Minh_City.html&quot;&gt;War Remnants Museum&lt;/a&gt;, which had a fair few military vehicles outside,  including tanks, and Chinook and an F-5A fighter jet. There was also a collection of the sort of bombs used throughout the war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the museum was a different story. In the first floor were evidence of outage from citizens of all countries against the Americans war in Vietnam. I took my time to get around the exhibits, and so didn’t get up the the top floor, but I did get to the second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second floor, on one side were graphic images and stories,  either from survivors or from journalists who accompanied the American troops. Survivors were few, and according to the exhibits, all Vietnamese in all villages were treated as Viet Cong. Women and children were all killed, not just men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the second floor was an exhibition of images and statistics regarding the impact of Agent Orange and other harmful chemicals used throughout the war, most of which contained the very harmful Dioxin. In a way this was worse than all the outright murder of many people,  due to the ongoing effects of poisoning the land and the people. Dioxin not only affects those initially poisoned with it, but through severe genetic mutation also affects their offspring, and their offsprings offspring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this weighing down heavy, and even more distaste for the Americans, we headed onwards to our next destination - the reunification palace. We only looked in from outside the gate,  but you could see that it was built with some grandeur, and the style was still rather modern despite its age. We continued on a walkabout tour, visiting a catholic church with French inspiration in the architecture, then across the road to the old post office building, which was in fact still in use, and I finally found a fee-free ATM within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some rest and recuperation time at the hotel (and swapping into our night rooms), we headed out to dinner to a place that specialises in pancakes (Vietnamese pancakes are savoury). Aside from being fried, you could probably call these pancakes quite healthy, as they’re made with rice flour, water and egg, so also great for those who eat gluten free. In Vietnam,  you don’t just eat a fried spring roll or a pancake by itself, instead you roll it up into a lettuce or cabbage leaf before dipping into the dipping sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we were due for another early morning, so now if us were about to hit the bar. We all slunk off to bed to get as much sleep as we could.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/10/vietnam-trip-day-14.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/10/vietnam-trip-day-14.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vietnam Trip - Day 13</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-13&quot;&gt;Day 13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sore head. Probably not as bad as it could have been, but I was definitely hungover. Thankfully, today was a free day, so I didn’t have to do too much. After taking a lot of rehydration salts and water, and after a greasy breakfast, I went out to run a few errands. This little ritual is reasonably similar to my usual hangover cure, whereas I would normally have a powerade and fish’n’chips (and of course a shower!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After collecting some bathroom supplies, I moved our bags across the hall to our the day room, as we would not be staying another night here. This room was already occupied by two of the Swiss girls, the other one having gone out for a day at the mud baths with my own travelling companions. They left shortly after to run their own errands. Since by this time I was rather hot and sweaty from being outside, I pulled up a chair and turned down the relatively ineffective air conditioning to chill out for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I still had some errands to run,  so I went out and got all that over and done with. Coming back to the hotel I found the girls had returned to the room. We all spent some time reading, but it easing long before all of us were napping - we’d all been out late the night before, after all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waking up again, a plan was formed to go to the beach, but not before lunch was obtained. I cannot recommend it, but we had lunch at the Seafood and Western Food Restaurant. This would be the second time I’d eat some kind of Western food by choice while on this trip. I had a chicken burger, and all of our meals came out very slowly,  and one after the other. By the time the first person finished their meal, the next persons meal was just coming out. Plus the burger bun was rock hard, despite it not being gluten free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After paying the bill, we crossed the road to the beach. We paid to sit under a breach umbrella (40,000 doing per person, or roughly $2 each), and I watched the bags while the rest went for a swim. I could have spent this time catching up on writing, but instead I relaxed and read for a while in the shade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not long before the mud-bathers returned and joined us, but it was also being late. Another hour on the beach and it was time to get back to the hotel and get ready to go. Tonight we were getting on yet another train, once again an overnighter, to Ho Chi Minh City, aka Saigon. Knowing we weren’t going to get dinner on the train, we changed out of our beach clothes and into something more city-friendly and headed out to dinner. Since my partner hadn’t gone out for dinner the night we arrived, we took her back to that restaurant (Lanterns), since the food had been rather good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my dismay, my two travelling companions both ordered fish and chips! Unfortunately instead of trying something new I went for the Simmering Pork, which I knew to be good from last time. Even though we had told some people where we’d be, nobody joined us, and we heard later that they’d actually gotten a little lost trying to find us, which I think is forgivable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a while to wait at the train station. The train was marginally late, which was just as well, as our tour guide’s clothes had still not come back from the laundry. While he went off to get his clothes, we were left a little confused each time we heard an announcement from the station, as none of it was in English. Was it our train arriving, or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully we all got onto the train alright, though not before a bit of confusion over which rooms would be occupied by whom. It was still early in the night, and our guide was still hungry after an unsatisfying dinner if his own, so a few of us joined him on an excursion to the restaurant carriage at the back of the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boy am I glad I didn’t eat train food. The carriage was a little worse for wear, and the off-duty cooks were smoking inside. Our guide still ordered some food - I suppose it is pretty hard to mess up instant noodles. We were really only there to socialise, so we had the token beer or water while he ate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we had an estimated 4:30am departure time, we headed back for an early night’s sleep. Unfortunately sleep did not come easy, and it did not come well. I was restless, and knew this would not fair overly well for the next day…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/09/vietnam-trip-day-13.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/09/vietnam-trip-day-13.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vietnam Trip - Day 12</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-12&quot;&gt;Day 12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nha Trang, to those who know it,  is a party beach city. This I can confirm. It is also full of Russians.  Through the war, Russia provided much support to the Vietnamese, and they rented a military base in the Nha Trang area. Now, there are many flights from Russia to Nha Trang, including direct flights from Moscow, making for quite a large population of Russians. So many in fact that unlike other parts of Vietnam where you’ll find a restaurant menu in Vietnamese and English, you’ll find some restaurants in Nha Trang that have menus primarily in Russian, and the staff might speak Russian instead of English (and of course always Vietnamese).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning of Day 12, we headed down to port,  optionally grabbed some flippers and jumped on a boat. It was a beautiful day, blue sky and plenty of sun, and in Nha Trang the water is safe to swim in! So on this day, this particular morning, we were going snorkelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed out to an island out in the bay. We wandered through the village,  getting some idea of island life as we went. On the other side of the island we got into another, smaller boat the shape of a bowl, one of the more traditional Vietnamese fishing boats. As we were loading in, we got to see one come in with a load of fish, which they proceeded to weigh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These little boats were really just taking us back to our original boat,  which had moved around the island to meet us. The body took us out to a reef just off the shore of another island and anchored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all changed into our togs and jumped into the water. It was refreshingly cool,  and I was happy to finally be able to immerse myself in a decent amount of water for the first time in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a swim, the crew served us lunch, which included prawns, fish, noodles, rice and spring rolls. For food on a boat I was impressed - it probably beat some restaurant food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a few more hours out on the boat,  some time spent swimming and some spent sun bathing. With sufficient application of sunblock, I myself choose to sun bathe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we returned to Nha Trang,  clouds were settling in. As we came into harbour, rain started to fall. It was quite nice really, a light, refreshing drizzle. It was about 3pm, so back at the hotel we had a few hours free time, which must of us used to shower and rest before dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say dinner was a token dinner,  having been fed fairly well for lunch and not exerting much energy. But we needed to have something in us - tonight we would experience some of the night life in Nha Trang. Being still quite early in the evening, most of us went to the first bar,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g293928-d782081-Reviews-Why_Not_Bar-Nha_Trang_Khanh_Hoa_Province.html&quot;&gt;Why Not? Bar&lt;/a&gt;. You could say we are preloading,  though I was also trying to double down on the water as well. I ordered a drink called the “Why Not? Bucket”, and soon learned why it had this name. The drink came out in an plastic jar,  probably about one litre worth. Well, tonight could only end well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this bar we lost a few people to their beds, wishing to keep their heads. The rest of us that were left - you might call us youngsters - headed off to our intended final drinking hole, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g293928-d1104316-Reviews-Sailing_Club_Nha_Trang-Nha_Trang_Khanh_Hoa_Province.html&quot;&gt;The Sailing Club&lt;/a&gt;. We got a free drink upon entry, although that’s debatable since there was a door charge. With the options of Heineken or a “Jam Jar”,  I kept my wits about me and went for the jam jar. Lo and behold, out came another vessel of the same form as the Why Not? Bucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sailing Club also had a dance floor, which suited us just fine. Walking up past the asian analogues of the white man dance, I took my partner by the hand and we put a little show. It felt a little sloppy but we’ve been slack with practice and were dancing in sandals, but that didn’t stop people pulling out their cameras and phones. Given that we were dancing Modern Jive to techno, it wasn’t long before we had to take a break… Well maybe for her, but our flatmate demanded a dance so I didn’t get to rest until I was quite sweaty (given the heat, this wasn’t long).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sailing Club sits on prime real estate on the beach,  so we retired out there where we could feel some of the nice sea breeze. By this time I was just drinking water, but that didn’t stop me from playing leap frog, managing to leap over three people, all the while feeling reasonably certain that I would fall short and take one of the others out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more dance (for the others) and we headed back to the hotel, which was practically just around the corner. I started loading myself with rehydrating salts, in hopes of preventing some part of the massive hangover I was rather likely due.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/08/vietnam-trip-day-12.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/08/vietnam-trip-day-12.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vietnam Trip - Day 11</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-11&quot;&gt;Day 11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nine o’clock was our designated time of departure. We ate, packed and loaded into the bus. Our tailored clothes had arrived during the evening while at dinner. All ready to go, we piled into another bus and headed back up to Da Nang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got off at Da Nang station. As per usual, with the trains running on Vietnam time our train was late, so we were sitting around in the station for about an hour. I passed the time by looking through the attached souvenir and food store,  getting a few snacks for the day trip to Nha Trang. I also amused myself watching Looper bring played on one of the screens, on mute and with Vietnamese subtitles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train was meant to take about 8 hours to get to Nha Trang. I think it ended up taking about 9 or 10. But that’s about standard, I’ve learnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Nha Trang,  we quickly got onto yet another bus, and rode off to our hotel. We arrived around about 9:30pm, but our tour guide still thought it’d be a good idea to have dinner. After checking in we headed out to a nearby restaurant called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g293928-d1515355-Reviews-Lanterns_Vietnamese_Restaurant-Nha_Trang_Khanh_Hoa_Province.html&quot;&gt;Lanterns&lt;/a&gt;. The food there was pretty good (I had the Simmering Pork in a Clay Pot), though I think many of us ate far too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bed wasn’t far away, and after a day of not much, sleep was very welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/07/vietnam-trip-day-11.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://brett.geek.nz/2014/04/07/vietnam-trip-day-11.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
